Guide to the Office of Study Abroad Records, 1982-Ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Office of Study Abroad records 1982-Ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences. Office of Study Abroad.
4.0 linear feet Extent: 1000 Items
Formal investigation into a study abroad program began in 1947 when Dean Alice Baldwin appointed a committee to study the status of existing opportunities for Duke students to study elsewhere and for foreign students to study at Duke. This collection contains correspondence, brochures, catalogs, clippings, photographs, a videotape, artifacts and other records. Some material in the collection focuses on the Hosei University (Tokyo) Summer Institute at Duke.
RL.01875
Language: Material in English, Japanese
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Office of Study Abroad Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1980.
Historical Note
As far as is known the first Duke students to study abroad were a small "foreign study group" who visited and took classes at the University of Dijon, France in 1927. Formal investigation into a study abroad program began in 1947 when Dean Alice Baldwin appointed a committee to study the status of existing opportunities for Duke students to study elsewhere and for foreign students to study at Duke. President Robert Flowers later made this committee a continuing university level committee.
Collection Overview
This collection contains correspondence, brochures, catalogs, clippings, photographs, a videotape, artifacts and other records. Some material in the collection focuses on the Hosei University (Tokyo) Summer Institute at Duke.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences; Students, Foreign -- North Carolina -- Durham
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, 1982-Ongoing, 4.0 Linear Feet (1 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
  - History (Box 1)
  - Catalogs and publicity
  - Brochures, flyers, etc.
  - Hosei University Summer Seminar, video, 1992
  - Hosei at Duke, 1993
  - Journals, 1993-1995, 1995, 1998
  - Hosei contracts, 1998
  - Junsuke Correspondence, 1998-1999
  - Hosei, miscellaneous info., 1998
  - Excursions, 1998
  - Hosei (Amanda)
  - Hosei, 1999
  - Hosei contracts, 1999
  - Hosei at Duke, Reminiscences, 1999
  - Hosei, miscellaneous, 2000
  - Hosei contracts, 2000
  - Hosei University, flag and banner
  - Hosei University Institute, photographs, 1990-2000
  - Study abroad photographs, 1980s-1990s
  - Study Abroad Photographs, circa 1987-1995 (Opaperfolder 1)